[Subtitles by danielsangeo]
Huh. Wow.
A drop this deep really makes
you wonder about the necessity
of having a chamber this size.
It's just as well that
green goo is down there.
If I thought it was water, I'd be tempted
to just jump off here and do a cannonball.
I bet I could get a splash
two stories high.
Is that a pixie?
Science hasn't disproven
the existence of pixies.
If they can shift through dimensions, that
would explain the lack of evidence for them.
What's this?
[lights clicking on]
I'm hearing clicking.
Pixies don't click.
[lights clicking on]
Is that you?
No. Hey, lights.
What?  Who did the--?
[metallic rumbling]
Oh. Good!
I can get out of here!
[metallic rumbling]
Hey, wait. That's not a pixie.
That's just some blue light.
This whole place is built on deception.
Screw it.
Going up.
No! Going up, dammit!
That's where I came from!
UP!
Argh! This is going to take for--
[metallic banging]
I guess I spoke too soon.
Uh.
[metallic groaning]
Jesus!
[metallic creaking]
I don't like this...
Okay, I'm in a rickety-ass elevator
[metallic creaking]
that's creaking. What do I do?
Get off it?
[metallic creaking]
Okay, that looks like a pipe.
[metallic groaning]
Looks like it might go somewhere.
Don't think I have a lot of options.
[metallic groaning]
Okay, I-I can jump this.
And the irony is,
[metallic groaning]
it's probably going to be one of the safer
jumps I've done this morning.
[metallic groaning]
Assuming I don't die.
[metallic creaking]
[electrical sparking, metallic banging]
Oh, man!
I climbed my way to safety!
I AM A MONKEY GOD!
[monkey calls]
[Geiger counter clicks]
That could be me right now,
a toxic human french fry.
[Geiger counter clicks]
But no, my simian skills saw me safely.
Hey, did you see that?
SCIENTIST: I hope no one expects me
Look at me! Look at me!
SCIENTIST: to start up the generator.
Smithers went down there and
SCIENTIST: never came back.
Oh, you think he escaped?
All right, here's the plan: you keep staring
at your dials and I'll get out of here.
I mean, I wouldn't come back
for you if I found an exit.
That's not my job.
[Geiger counter clicks]
Ah, tick-tick-tock.
Is that the sound of a Geiger counter
[Geiger counter clicks]
or is my lifespan counting down?
It's both!
[Geiger counter clicks]
That's right, here at Black Mesa,
when we talk about half-life,
[Geiger counter clicks]
we mean it more ways than one.
So, make your peace and
[Geiger counter clicks]
come to Black Mesa.
Here, you'll win a chance to
fight freaks of nature,
escape countless safety hazards,
wander aimlessly for hours,
[bullsquid spits]
and die scared, tired and alone.
Where's that noise coming from?
[bullsquid spits]
Yeah, I'm calling you out, noise.
Oh, it's you.
[bullsquid spits]
This is almost getting to be like a chore.
Y'know, wash the dishes,
do the laundry,
shoot the snot thing,
empty the trash...
It's all just a blur.
What's this do?
WHOA!
Nnnnnnyyyeeeeow!
That was awesome, let's do it again.
[whistles]
AGAIN!
Eh, no, better not.
I could do this all day.
I'm never going to rich enough to
buy my own island if I keep this up.
Wow.
Yeah, it's like that experiment with rats,
where every hour they're given
the choice between food
or having the pleasure center of
their brain stimulated
and the rats starve to death every time.
Hup!
You know, that first ride was fun but
this one looks kind of dangerous.
It's just slamming back and forth.
Whoa-ho. Yeah, you can feel THAT passing.
That'll knock your head off like
one of those little tee-ball sticks.
That's snap, crackle, and pop
all in one package.
Ah, a button.
Well, my work here is done.
Hey, are you a monkey, too?
[monkey call]
SMITHERS: This is my hiding
spot, and I'm not moving
SMITHERS: until the situation
has drastically improved.
SMITHERS: Now go away!
And don't tell anyone I'm here!
Okay, I'm going to call you Mr. Fantastic.
Or wait, no, Doc-Doctor Amazing.
Doctor Amazing.
Ah hah.
Well, that was anticlimactic.
I was hoping that some music would
start playing if I pressed both of them.
Y'know, it would be cool if we could get
a dance party going on up here, like a rave?
I bet the acoustics of this room
would be interesting.
[boom]
SMITHERS: AAAH!
What?!
SMITHERS: OH DEAR!
Man, you're not going to be missed.
Nobody's going to come looking for you.
[electrical humming and crackling]
Uh...wait a minute.
Okay, we're not electrocuted...
[electrical humming and crackling]
I've determined that much...
but... um... not seeing a way down... now...
[electrical humming and crackling]
Umm... shit.
I think I fucked up.
[electrical humming and crackling]
I think I fucked up, man.
I... shouldn't... press buttons without...
[electrical humming and crackling]
knowing what they do first...
Oh, oh, okay.  We can get down--
[electrical humming and crackling]
I mean, I can get down here.
Okay, I'll just lower myself down
[electrical humming and crackling]
and be careful about the landing.
Oooh... okay... um.... that's pretty scary...
[electrical humming and crackling]
Yaaahh....!
God dammit, Earth's gravity shouldn't
even be this strong for a planet our size.
It's only this way because there's
so many metals in the core
increasing its overall density so that--
Oh fuck, I'm going to have to jump here.
Okay, lower myself down...
to reduce the VERtical... drop...!
Now, time it so I don't get
sideswiped by the cart of death...
And...
Aaagh... rrr...
Okay...
Yeah...
I'm just going to take it easy.
God, that would've been so
much easier if I was drunk.
I mean, not piss-drunk, but
y'know, just like a heavy buzz.
I would've been fearless,
wouldn't have hurt my knees at all.
This sucks sober!
Life sucks sober!
Oh God oh God oh God
oh God oh God...oh God...
Okay, I think coming this way
has the biggest waste of time
I've accomplished in a while.
That's saying a lot.
I mean it's not like I just went down
the wrong corridor, like I sometimes do.
No, it's--WHEEEEEEEEEEEEEEEEEEEEEEEEEEEEEEEE!
It's worse than that.
Hey, that looks kind of cool.
I want a giant metal spider fortress.
What was I thinking about?
Oh yeah, this place sucks.
[Geiger counter clicks]
How could I forget?
Yeah, when I go down a dead-end here,
[Geiger counter clicks]
I go down a DEAD-END!
Meaning, I go off course for, like, miles,
[Geiger counter clicks]
ten stories underground, and I almost die.
A lot.
SCIENTIST: Excellent!
Yoo-hoo!
SCIENTIST: Someone has restored all power.
SCIENTIST: We'll have the engine
up again in no time!
Yeah, that room's dangerous.
Did you know that?
It's a good thing I made it back okay.
I was gonna... yedduh... yes, master...
No, stop!
You can't kill me, so you're going
to try and control me, IS THAT IT!?!
[Geiger counter clicks]
I'LL NEVER DO YOUR BIDDING!
I HAVE A DOCTOR'S DEGREE!
[Geiger counter clicks]
Wait, how am I going to get out of here?
I should've thought about this sooner...
[Geiger counter clicks]